<oml:data_set_description xmlns:oml="http://openml.org/openml">
  <oml:id>218</oml:id>
  <oml:name>house_8L</oml:name>
  <oml:version>1</oml:version>
  <oml:description>**Author**:   
**Source**: Unknown -   
**Please cite**:   

This database was designed on the basis of data provided by US Census
 Bureau [http://www.census.gov] (under Lookup Access
 [http://www.census.gov/cdrom/lookup]: Summary Tape File 1). The data
 were collected as part of the 1990 US census. These are mostly counts
 cumulated at different survey levels. For the purpose of this data set
 a level State-Place was used. Data from all states was obtained. Most
 of the counts were changed into appropriate proportions.  There are 4
 different data sets obtained from this database: House(8H) House(8L)
 House(16H) House(16L) These are all concerned with predicting the
 median price of the house in the region based on demographic
 composition and a state of housing market in the region. A number in
 the name signifies the number of attributes of the data set. A
 following letter denotes a very rough approximation to the difficulty
 of the task. For Low task difficulty, more correlated attributes were
 chosen as signified by univariate smooth fit of that input on the
 target. Tasks with High difficulty have had their attributes chosen to
 make the modelling more difficult due to higher variance or lower
 correlation of the inputs to the target.
 
 Original source: DELVE repository of data. 
 Source: collection of regression datasets by Luis Torgo (ltorgo@ncc.up.pt) at
 http://www.ncc.up.pt/~ltorgo/Regression/DataSets.html
 Characteristics: 22784 cases, 9 continuous attributes.</oml:description>
  <oml:description_version>1</oml:description_version>
  <oml:format>ARFF</oml:format>
        <oml:upload_date>2014-04-23T13:18:38</oml:upload_date>
    <oml:licence>Public</oml:licence>  <oml:url>https://api.openml.org/data/v1/download/3655/house_8L.arff</oml:url>
  <oml:parquet_url>https://openml1.win.tue.nl/datasets/0000/0218/dataset_218.pq</oml:parquet_url>  <oml:file_id>3655</oml:file_id>  <oml:default_target_attribute>price</oml:default_target_attribute>      <oml:version_label>1</oml:version_label>    <oml:tag>Demographics</oml:tag><oml:tag>Economics</oml:tag>  <oml:visibility>public</oml:visibility>      <oml:minio_url>https://openml1.win.tue.nl/datasets/0000/0218/dataset_218.pq</oml:minio_url>  <oml:status>active</oml:status>
  <oml:processing_date>2020-11-20 20:27:37</oml:processing_date>      <oml:md5_checksum>36801c359064386f44f4da0366c1837e</oml:md5_checksum>
</oml:data_set_description>
