<oml:data_set_description xmlns:oml="http://openml.org/openml">
  <oml:id>350</oml:id>
  <oml:name>webdata_wXa</oml:name>
  <oml:version>1</oml:version>
  <oml:description>**Author**: John Platt  
**Source**: [libSVM](http://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/~cjlin/libsvmtools/datasets) - Date unknown  
**Please cite**:   John C. Platt. 
Fast training of support vector machines using sequential minimal optimization. 
In Bernhard Schölkopf, Christopher J. C. Burges, and Alexander J. Smola, editors, Advances in Kernel Methods - Support Vector Learning, Cambridge, MA, 1998. MIT Press.a

This is the famous webdata dataset w[1-8]a in its binary version, retrieved 2014-11-14 from the libSVM site. Additional to the preprocessing done there (see LibSVM site for details), this dataset was created as follows: 

* load all web data  datasets, train and test, e.g. w1a, w1a.t, w2a, w2a.t, w3a, ... 
* join test and train for each subset, e.g. w1a and w1a.t, w2a and w2a.t 
* normalize each file columnwise according to the following rules: 
* If a column only contains one value (constant feature), it will set to zero and thus removed by sparsity. 
* If a column contains two values (binary feature), the value occuring more often will be set to zero, the other to one. 
* If a column contains more than two values (multinary/real feature), the column is divided by its std deviation.
* afterwards all these 8 files are merged into one, and randomly sorted. 
* duplicate lines were finally removed.

An R script which does all of these steps can be found here:
https://github.com/openml/data_scripts/blob/master/webdata_wXa/dataDownloader.R</oml:description>
  <oml:description_version>1</oml:description_version>
  <oml:format>Sparse_ARFF</oml:format>
  <oml:creator>John Platt</oml:creator>     <oml:collection_date>1998</oml:collection_date>  <oml:upload_date>2014-08-29T18:29:14</oml:upload_date>
  <oml:language>English</oml:language>  <oml:licence>Public</oml:licence>  <oml:url>https://api.openml.org/data/v1/download/52253/webdata_wXa.sparse_arff</oml:url>
    <oml:file_id>52253</oml:file_id>  <oml:default_target_attribute>Y</oml:default_target_attribute>        <oml:citation>John C. Platt.  Fast training of support vector machines using sequential minimal optimization.  In Bernhard Scholkopf, Christopher J. C. Burges, and Alexander J. Smola, editors, Advances in Kernel Methods - Support Vector Learning, Cambridge, MA</oml:citation>  <oml:tag>Computer Systems</oml:tag><oml:tag>Machine Learning</oml:tag><oml:tag>mythbusting_1</oml:tag><oml:tag>study_1</oml:tag><oml:tag>study_15</oml:tag><oml:tag>study_20</oml:tag><oml:tag>study_34</oml:tag><oml:tag>study_41</oml:tag>  <oml:visibility>public</oml:visibility>  <oml:original_data_url>http://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/~cjlin/libsvmtools/datasets</oml:original_data_url>  <oml:paper_url>https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/4731075</oml:paper_url>    <oml:status>active</oml:status>
  <oml:processing_date>2020-11-20 19:44:57</oml:processing_date>      <oml:md5_checksum>e35d0578373c6100a62354ca4d16744a</oml:md5_checksum>
</oml:data_set_description>
